<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="tomba_antenore_title">Antenor's Tomb</string>
    <string name="tomba_antenore_text">
According to Greek-Roman tradition, Antenor (Antenore in Italian) was the legendary founder
of Padua.
In the Iliad, Antenor is a noble wise man of Troy who first seeks to avoid a clash with the
Greeks, encouraging negotiations with Menelaus and Ulysses, and thereafter requests that Helen
be returned to her Greek husband in order to put an end to the war.
Later texts tell of his journey across the Mediterranean after Troy was destroyed, of his arrival on
the shores of Venice and foundation of Padua, as a new home for the surviving Trojans.
Yet the positive image we have of Antenor, sustained by Titus Livius Patavinus (57 BC - 17 AD)
and Virgil (70 BC - 19 BC) is flanked by a negative version, which portrays him as a traitor and
the cause of the Trojan defeat.
This vision is exacerbated in Mediaeval knightly tales and taken up by Dante, who in his Divine
Comedy names the round in the circle of hell where traitors of their countries are punished
“ Antenorea ”.
In Padua, the legend is revived in the Age of the Communes. Judge and poet Lovato Lovati
(1240- 1309) promoted the construction of a monument in celebration of Antenor, which was
completed by the municipality in 1283-1285 (according to two stone plaques on the aedicule): a
sarcophagus dating to the Late Antiquity, holding what are believed to be the remains of the
legendary founder (although in actual fact, modern scientific investigations date the body in the
sepulchre to between the 2nd and 5th century AD), and an aedicule featuring columns and
arches, originally adjoined to the church of San Lorenzo, which was knocked down in 1937 to
open up to the current piazza.
Lovato composed the inscription carved into the sarcophagus, taking up texts by Livius and
Virgil. A translation (translated here from the version by Giorgio Ronconi) of his difficult
pre-humanistic Latin reads: “ Noble Antenor, supporter of domestic peace, here brought the fugitive Eneti and
Dardanians [Trojans], crushed the Euganei and founded the city of Padua: here is his home, carved into humble
marble. ”
At a time when political dynamics were usually solved through war and violence, Lovato presents
the people of Padua not so much with the Trojan hero’s wartime value, but highlights the role of
Antenor as pacifier, a civic model to be imitated
    </string>

    <string name="ponte_torricelle_title">Epigraph to the Torricelle Bridge</string>
    <string name="ponte_torricelle_text">
    This epigraph was originally located on the Torricelle Gate when it was constructed in 1210.
    When the gate was knocked down in 1819, the stone plaque was positioned on a home, before
    ending up where it is today, in Via Roma.
    The epigraph is carved into Nanto stone and positioned under another stone that recalls the
    entrance by Ezzelino da Romano in 1237.
    The Latin text in ten hexameters was dictated by Giovanni Valdetaro, a grammarian amongst
    the entourage of the Podesta in office, Giacomo Landi from Piacenza, as the official
    certification of Padua municipality. The translation reads:
    “ The nobleman Giacomo Landi, native to Piacenza, deservedly Podesta of Padua, in 1210 adorned the city
    with walls and a gate facing south. O sons of Antenor, if you wish to be safe from the enemy outside, Peace will
    bind you within, with a wall of love. In vain is the shade sought under a leafy tree if an acute disease corrodes our
    bladders within.
    If the fatigue and the expense of the wall is not to be wasted, listen to the counsel of your poet Giovanni ”
    The text refers to the construction of a new part of the city walls, which connected the Gate to
    the Castle running along the canal in lieu of the previous ones.
    The concerned invitation of the local authorities for harmony amongst the citizens is expressed
    in a period of great social and political change, with frequent internal divisions and violent
    clashes.
    Only one other inscription is known with similar contents and dating to the same period, in the
    city of Bremen.
    </string>

</resources>
