<resources>
    <!-- Customize your app's name here. -->
    <string name="app_name">Appace</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Appace - Map</string>
    <!-- -->

    <string name="gps_disabled">GPS disattivato</string>
    <string name="gps_enabled">GPS attivato</string>
    <string name="conn_failed">Connessione fallita</string>
    <string name="conn_suspended">Connessione sospesa</string>


    <string name="menu_mapStyle_title">Stile Mappa</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_summary">Scegli il tipo di mappa di Google Maps</string>
    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_title">Soglia di Zoom</string>
    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_summary">Soglia oltre la quale scompare il pulsante per impostare il marker</string>
    <string name="menu_checkBox_title">Aggiornamento Automatico</string>
    <string name="menu_checkBox_summary">Verifica la presenza di versioni più recenti.</string>

    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_low">Basso</string>
    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_mid">Medio</string>
    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_high">Alto</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_normal">Standard</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_satellite">Satellite</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_terrain">Terreno</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_hybrid">Ibrido</string>

    <string name="credits_year">2018</string>
    <string name="credits_project">CEVID</string>
    <string name="credits_company">Università Ca\' Foscari Venezia</string>
    <string name="credits_authors">Alessio Camata, Alvise Spanò</string>

    <string name="action_info">Info</string>
    <string name="action_impostazioni">Impostazioni</string>

    <string name="msg_loading">Caricamento…</string>
    <string name="msg_button_car">Pulsante premuto</string>
    <string name="msg_permissions_not_granted">I permessi appena negati dall\'utente sono necessari per alcune funzionalità dell\'app. Il supporto delle funzionalità sarà ridotto.</string>
    <string name="marker_title">You are HERE</string>
    <string name="logo_descr">Università Ca\' Foscari, Venezia</string>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling">ScrollingActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_presentation">PresentationActivity</string>

    <string name="presentation">
        <b>Presentazione</b>"\n"

"Just three years after the printing of the second edition, that was distributed to the local peace supporters who greatly appreciated that, we are now happy to introduce the third edition of this guide, this time available as an app for smartphones.
The English translation has been considered essential for giving the large number of foreign tourists, who are fond of peace matters, the opportunity to use the guide and appreciate its contents.
Through the correction of some minor mistakes and the insertion of new, original pictures, the guide is now more precise and more documented. The new location of two points of interest has been also here reported.
We would like to remind the readers that this guide offers an alternative way to discover the city. It takes a rather unusual approach for a guide, promoting a culture of peace and nonviolence.
\n\n"
        <b>Progetti internazionali</b>"\n"
"The idea stems from the international contacts established through the Grundtvig European programme, “Discover Peace in Europe”, financed by the European Union, which led to the creation of routes of peace in 7 more European cities: Turin, Paris, Vienna, Berlin, Budapest, The Hague and Manchester. A website showing these peace routes has also been published1.
The first city to prepare a peace trail was Bradford (GB). The route has been published as a booklet of about 40 pages.
A pocket book of 212 pages has also been produced in Vienna (A), presenting the city in these terms2. And a great many other cities across the globe have prepared similar routes in order to ensure due consideration of the culture of peace and nonviolence, starting from the local context. These include others in Great Britain (London, Coventry and Leeds), as well as Atlanta in the USA3, which in addition to the website has also produced a 64-page booklet, and Geneva in Switzerland4.
\n\n"
        <b>In Italia</b>"\n"

"Padua is the first city to have produced a guide of this scope.
Meanwhile, in Turin, a similar guide has been published in two versions, one written in Italian and another one translated into English. The aforementioned Grundtvig programme is the reference background in which this work has been conceived and published.
\n\n"
        <b>I criteri di scelta</b>"\n"
"The places, people and histories are presented in the form of short summaries. The choices made were to present places and people that had taken positive action for peace and nonviolence and as such reference to places of war, which unfortunately abound in Padua, have been limited, but not forgotten. We researched the many traces, throughout the territory of Padua, which at times can prove difficult to identify, of those who sought to act in favour of peace, reconciliation and justice over the centuries, avoiding, refusing or minimising the use of violence, even if not specifically referring to the idea of nonviolence, but rather to other positive human, religious or political values. The culture of peace is an ancient one, but the culture of nonviolence is young. It is therefore not correct to label aspects of the distant past with the term “nonviolence”, when reflection on this method of action, in its precise, moral, cultural and political sense, only dates back to the last century. We had to make choices and this has sometimes meant glossing over episodes and people that others may consider important.\n\n"
        <b>Le schede</b>"\n"

"The part dedicated to pre-twentieth century history is fairly brief.
We investigated a great many famous people, but in the end, many proved to be incoherent with the criteria we had set ourselves. Some of the most famous people we had to exclude were Bernardino da Feltre, the founder of the Monte di Pietà, an institution we can perhaps consider as a distant forerunner of ethical finance, but whom we had to exclude on the grounds of his fanatical anti-Semitism. The same applied to Galileo Galilei, the great scientist who worked not only for pure research, but also to create war machines. Unfortunately, eight hundred years of history of Padua University turned up very few examples of pioneers of a culture of peace.
The part on twentieth century history is fairly extensive, but could potentially be even greater.
Padua has been an important military hub and victim of a great deal of war violence, starting with the bombing.
However, it has also been a place of resistance and actions of peace; a place of welcome for the persecuted, like the Armenians. This section includes information on monuments dedicated to the memory of the victims and the “righteous”, which abound particularly in Padua, as well as summaries on individual people. Others could certainly be added, particularly in the period of the Resistance movement.
Finally, the contemporary part provides examples of the current culture of peace experienced in Padua. It is not intended, indeed it would be impossible, as a complete list of all movements present in the city and their work, information on which is readily available from the various websites and brochures that change rapidly; rather, we aim to provide a mere indication of places, people and subject matters that have been important, encouraging further personal research at will.
We hope that this third edition of the guide will be followed by further, more complete editions, also incorporating any reader suggestions. At the end of the guide, a bibliography gives suggestions of additional reading materials.
Enjoy!
\n\n"
        <b>Movimento Internazionale della Riconciliazione, sede di Padova</b>"\n"
"
1)	http://www.discoverpeace.eu
2)	E. Hewson, G. Hamann, S. Jalka, Frieden entdecken in Wien, Pro Business, Vienna, 2011
3)	http://www.atlantapeacetrails.com
4)	http://www.genevaforpeace.com, Itinéraire de la paix"


    </string>

    <string name="luoghi_pace_button">PLACES OF PEACE</string>
    <string name="fonti_button">FONTS</string>
    <string name="crediti_button">CREDITS</string>
    <string name="presentazione_button">PRESENTATION</string>
</resources>
