<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">Appace</string>

    <string name="gps_disabled">GPS disattivato</string>
    <string name="gps_enabled">GPS attivato</string>
    <string name="conn_failed">Connessione fallita</string>
    <string name="conn_suspended">Connessione sospesa</string>

    <string name="menu_mapStyle_title">Stile Mappa</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_summary">Scegli il tipo di mappa di Google Maps</string>
    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_title">Soglia di Zoom</string>
    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_summary">Soglia oltre la quale scompare il pulsante per impostare il marker</string>
    <string name="menu_checkBox_title">Aggiornamento Automatico</string>
    <string name="menu_checkBox_summary">Verifica la presenza di versioni più recenti.</string>

    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_low">Basso</string>
    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_mid">Medio</string>
    <string name="menu_zoomThreshold_high">Alto</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_normal">Standard</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_satellite">Satellite</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_terrain">Terreno</string>
    <string name="menu_mapStyle_hybrid">Ibrido</string>

    <string name="credits_year">2018</string>
    <string name="credits_project">Appace</string>
    <string name="credits_company">Università Ca\' Foscari, Venice, Italy</string>
    <string name="credits_authors">Alvise Spanò</string>

    <string name="action_info">Info</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="msg_loading">Loading…</string>
    <string name="msg_button_car">Pressed</string>
    <string name="msg_permissions_not_granted">I permessi appena negati dall\'utente sono necessari per alcune funzionalità dell\'app. Il supporto delle funzionalità sarà ridotto.</string>

    <string name="marker_title">You are HERE</string>

    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map of Places</string>
    <string name="title_activity_presentation">Presentation</string>
    <string name="title_activity_site"><!--non inserire testo--></string>
    <string name="title_activity_sources">Sources</string>
    <string name="title_activity_list">Places of Peace</string>

    <string name="sitemap_button">MAP OF PLACES</string>
    <string name="sources_button">SOURCES</string>
    <string name="credits_button">CREDITS</string>
    <string name="presentation_button">PRESENTATION</string>
    <string name="sitelist_button">PLACES OF PEACE</string>

    <string name="imageview_default_contentdescription">Image</string>

    <string name="presentation_header_text">
    <b>ROUTES OF PEACE AND NONVIOLENCE IN PADUA</b>
        \n
    Places, people, events and experiences
    </string>


    <string name="presentation_text">
<i>“A good use of memory is one that serves a just cause and does not content itself with reproducing the past.”</i>
        \n
- Tzvetan Todorov, “Hope and Memory”, Ed. Garzanti
\n\n
<b>Presentation</b>\n\n
Just three years after the printing of the second edition, that was distributed to the local peace supporters who greatly appreciated that, we are now happy to introduce the third edition of this guide, this time available as an app for smartphones.
The English translation has been considered essential for giving the large number of foreign tourists, who are fond of peace matters, the opportunity to use the guide and appreciate its contents.
Through the correction of some minor mistakes and the insertion of new, original pictures, the guide is now more precise and more documented. The new location of two points of interest has been also here reported.
We would like to remind the readers that this guide offers an alternative way to discover the city. It takes a rather unusual approach for a guide, promoting a culture of peace and nonviolence.
\n\n
        <b>International Projects</b>\n\n
The idea stems from the international contacts established through the Grundtvig European
programme, “Discover Peace in Europe”, financed by the European Union, which led to the
creation of routes of peace in 7 more European cities: Turin, Paris, Vienna, Berlin, Budapest,
The Hague and Manchester. A website showing these peace routes has also been published (1).
The first city to prepare a peace trail was Bradford (GB). The route has been published as a
booklet of about 40 pages.
A pocket book of 212 pages has also been produced in Vienna (A), presenting the city in these
terms (2). And a great many other cities across the globe have prepared similar routes in order to
ensure due consideration of the culture of peace and nonviolence, starting from the local
context. These include others in Great Britain (London, Coventry and Leeds), as well as Atlanta
in the USA (3), which in addition to the website has also produced a 64-page booklet, and Geneva
in Switzerland (4).
        \n\n
        <b>In Italy</b>\n\n
Padua is the first city tohave produced a guide of this scope.
Meanwhile, in Turin, a similar guide has been published in two versions, one written in Italian and another one translated into English. The aforementioned Grundtvig programme is the reference background in which this work has been conceived and published.
\n\n
        <b>Choice Criteria</b>\n\n
The places, people and histories are presented in the form of short summaries. The choices made were to present places and people that had taken positive action for peace and nonviolence and as such reference to places of war, which unfortunately abound in Padua, have been limited, but not forgotten. We researched the many traces, throughout the territory of Padua, which at times can prove difficult to identify, of those who sought to act in favour of peace, reconciliation and justice over the centuries, avoiding, refusing or minimising the use of violence, even if not specifically referring to the idea of nonviolence, but rather to other positive human, religious or political values. The culture of peace is an ancient one, but the culture of nonviolence is young. It is therefore not correct to label aspects of the distant past with the term “nonviolence”, when reflection on this method of action, in its precise, moral, cultural and political sense, only dates back to the last century. We had to make choices and this has sometimes meant glossing over episodes and people that others may consider important.
\n\n
        <b>The Summaries</b>\n\n
The part dedicated to pre-twentieth century history is fairly brief.
We investigated a great many famous people, but in the end, many proved to be incoherent with the criteria we had set ourselves. Some of the most famous people we had to exclude were Bernardino da Feltre, the founder of the Monte di Pietà, an institution we can perhaps consider as a distant forerunner of ethical finance, but whom we had to exclude on the grounds of his fanatical anti-Semitism. The same applied to Galileo Galilei, the great scientist who worked not only for pure research, but also to create war machines. Unfortunately, eight hundred years of history of Padua University turned up very few examples of pioneers of a culture of peace.
The part on twentieth century history is fairly extensive, but could potentially be even greater.
Padua has been an important military hub and victim of a great deal of war violence, starting with the bombing.
However, it has also been a place of resistance and actions of peace; a place of welcome for the persecuted, like the Armenians. This section includes information on monuments dedicated to the memory of the victims and the “righteous”, which abound particularly in Padua, as well as summaries on individual people. Others could certainly be added, particularly in the period of the Resistance movement.
Finally, the contemporary part provides examples of the current culture of peace experienced in Padua. It is not intended, indeed it would be impossible, as a complete list of all movements present in the city and their work, information on which is readily available from the various websites and brochures that change rapidly; rather, we aim to provide a mere indication of places, people and subject matters that have been important, encouraging further personal research at will.
We hope that this third edition of the guide will be followed by further, more complete editions, also incorporating any reader suggestions. At the end of the guide, a bibliography gives suggestions of additional reading materials.
Enjoy!
\n\n
        <b>Movimento Internazionale della Riconciliazione, Padua offices</b>\n\n

(1)	http://www.discoverpeace.eu\n
(2)	E. Hewson, G. Hamann, S. Jalka, Frieden entdecken in Wien, Pro Business, Vienna, 2011\n
(3)	http://www.atlantapeacetrails.com\n
(4)	http://www.genevaforpeace.com, Itinéraire de la paix"\n

    </string>

    <string name="sources_text">
    <b>Literary sources and suggested bibliography</b>

"\n\nAccattoli Luigi, La radice di un grande albero. Francesco Canova, medico, missionario, cosmopolita, Ed. S. Paolo, 2013;\n
Arslan Antonia, La masseria delle allodole, Ed. Rizzoli, 2004;\n
AA.VV., Dizionario letterario delle opere e dei personaggi, Ed.Valentino Bompiani, Milano, 1950;\n
AA.VV., Padova per Antenore, Atti della giornata di studio (Padova, 14 dicembre 1989), a cura di G. Zampieri, Editoriale Programma, Padova, 1990;\n
AA.VV., Strade della Resistenza, Comune di Padova, Quartiere 3 EST, 2005;\n\nAA.VV., Un frate eroe della resistenza, Dolo (VE);\n
Braccesi Lorenzo, La leggenda di Antenore. Da Troia a Padova, Ed. Marsilio, Padova, 1984;\n\nButturini Giuseppe, Una professione che diventa missione. Francesco Canova e Medici con l’Africa Cuamm, Ed. Studium, 2013;\n
Collodo S., Padova al tempo di Francesco Petrarca in "Petrarca e il suo tempo, Catalogo della mostra "Petrarca e il suo tempo" Comune di Padova 8 maggio - 31 luglio 2004, Milano, Ed. Skira 2006;\n\nDaniele Ireneo, S. Antonio di Padova, Conversazioni sulla sua vita, Ed. Associazione Universale di S. Antonio, Padova, 1984;\n\n
Deaglio Enrico, La banalità del bene. Storia di Giorgio Perlasca, Ed. Feltrinelli, 2003;\n\n
Emerton Ephraim, The Defensor Pacis of Marsiglio of Padua, Oxford University Press, 1920;\n\nFabris Giovanni, Scritti di arte e storia padovana, Ed. Rebellato, Padova, 1977;\n\n
Franceschini Ezio, Concetto Marchesi, Ed. Antenore, Padova, 1978;\n\n
Gamboso Vergilio, Vita di sant’Antonio, Ed. Messaggero, Padova, 2011;\n\n
Geyer Francesco Saverio, Mons Daniele Comboni, Ed. Biblioteca Comboniana, 2000;\n\n
Jevnikar Ivo,Tottoli Apollonio ( a cura di), Padova-Chiesanuova, Un campo di concentramento e la carità di un frate, Ed. Over-Oltre, Padova 2009;\n\n
Lamon Roberta, Le statue di Palazzo Scarpari, “Padova e il suo territorio”, 156, aprile 2012, p. 18-21;\n\n
Lenci G., Le giornate di villa Giusti. Storia di un armistizio, Ed. Il Poligrafo, 2008;\n\n
Martini Carla Liliana, Catena di salvezza, Ed. Messaggero, Padova, 2005;\n\n
Puppi L., Toffanin G., Guida di Padova, Ed. Lint, Trieste, 1983;\n\n
Ronconi Giorgio, Antenore, la sua tomba, il suo mito, “Padova e il suo territorio”, I, 1986, n. 1, pp. 8-11;\n\n
Toffanin Giuseppe Junior, Cent’anni in una città, Ed. Rebellato, Padova, 1973;\n\n
Todorov Tzvetan, Di fronte all’estremo, Ed. Garzanti, 1992;\n\n
Todorov Tzvetan, Hope and Memory, Published by Princeton University Press, 2003;\n\n
Vasoin Gigi: “La Signoria dei Carraresi nella Padova del ‘300”, Ed. la Garangola Padova, 1988\n\n
Vecchia Giuliana, Breve storia del tempio della Pace, Tip. “La Garangola”, Padova, 1988;\n\n
Zilli Arturo, Dio non uccide, Ed. Il Margine, 2012.\n
        \n
        <b>Acknowledgements</b>\n\n
The photographs illustrating this guide have been taken thanks to the willingness of so many
people and institutions who have kindly opened the doors of their private homes, offices and
structures to allow us to obtain the results we have. Without this collaboration, certain images,
taken from unusual angles, would not have been possible, and certain works of art could not
have been included. We would therefore like to thank: Ms Dan and the staff of Banca
Antonveneta in the offices of Via VIII Febbraio, Marco Piccolo of Banca Popolare Etica, the
security staff of Padua University, the Comboni Father Celestino Prevedello, Chiara Giacon
and Father Luciano Bertazzo of the Centro Studi Antoniani and Loriana Puggelli Abati. Our
thanks also go to the administrative staff of the former Councillor Dalla Vecchia for their
exemplary collaboration.\n
\n
        <i>Sergio Bergami</i>
</string>

    <string name="credits" tools:ignore="TypographyOther">
    Photos and text by MIR\n
    - Movimento Internazionale Riconciliazione\n
    \n
    From «Routes of peace and nonviolence in Padua»,
    Tipografia Imprimenda, Limena (pd)\n
    \n
    App development:\ndr. Alvise Spanò\n
    \n
    Coordinator:\nprof. Agostino Cortesi\n
    \n
    (c) 2018\n
    Università Ca\' Foscari Venezia
    </string>

    <string name="credits2">
        <b>Routes of peace and nonviolence in Padua</b>\n
    Third edition, May 2018
Project by the Movimento Internazionale della Riconciliazione, Padua offices, 1/A Via
Cornaro, Padua, Italy.
Website: www.mirpadova.org
English translation sponsored by the Padua City Council.\n
    \n
    <b>The following people collaborated towards the preparation of this publication</b>:
    Andrea Alessandrini, Luca Baggio, Sergio Bergami, Antonia Carone, Claudio Carrara,
    Giampaolo Frison, Alfeo Merlin, Mariacristina Tassan, Francesco Varotto, Alberto Zangheri
    Scheda su Francesco Canova a cura di Linda Previato, Medici con l’Africa Cuamm.\n
    \n
    <b>Photography::</b>
        <i>“Sant’Antonio affronta il tiranno Ezzelino da Romano”</i> (Saint Anthony faces up to the tyrant
Ezzelino da Romano), photograph by Sergio Bergami (2013), courtesy of the “Centro Studi
Antoniani” (Study Centre of the Basilica of St. Anthony).
All other photographs are by Sergio Bergami (2012, 2013, 2014, 2015, 2018)
with the exception of:\n
- Placido Cortese (<i>Messaggero di S. Antonio, licensed under the Creative Commons</i>);\n
     - Concetto Marchesi, Mario Todesco, Silvio Barbato (<i>Wikipedia</i>);\n
     - Mariano Girotto (<i>Varotto\'s family</i>);\n
     - Tempio dell’Internato Ignoto e Giardino dei Giusti (<i>Giampaolo Frison</i>);\n
     - Francesco Canova (<i>Medici con l’Africa, Cuamm</i>);\n
     - <i>“S. Antonio restituisce la pace ai padovani”</i>(Saint Anthony restores peace to the people of
Padua), courtesy of the photographic library of the “Centro Studi Antoniani” (Prot. 092/13 of
23/04/2013).\n
- Portrait of Francesco Petrarca by Altichiero da Verona (<i>photograph: Wikimedia Commons</i>)\n
    \n
    <b>Translation of the summaries by</b>:\n
    Helen Tamara Matthews\n
    \n
    <b>Additional translations by</b>:\n
    Francesco Varotto\n
    \n
    <b>Revised by</b>:\n
    Francesco Varotto, Alberto Zangheri\n
    \n
    <b>Graphics and DTP</b>:\n
    Francesco Varotto\n
    \n
    <b>Printed by</b>:\n
    Imprimenda, Limena (PD)\n
    \n
    The MIR of Padua would like to thank anyone wishing to make suggestions or provide useful
information to supplement and amend this guide. Please e-mail any such recommendations to:
mirsezpd@libero.it.\n\n
No part of the texts can be reproduced using electronic, mechanical or any other means, unless
authorised in writing by the MIR of Padua.
    </string>

    <string name="site_string_not_found_error">
        \n
        <b>Error: string resource not found.</b>\n
        \n
        In case this error occurs, contact the author:\n
        \n
        alvise.spano@unive.it
    </string>


</resources>